<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/atom.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/atom.css" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
	<title>Mihai Nicolae</title>
	<updated>2020-01-11T10:24:03-08:00</updated>

	<subtitle>Hi, my name is Mihai Nicolae. I am a software engineer working in the Bay Area. Welcome to my personal website.</subtitle>

	
		
		<author>
			
				<name>mnicolae</name>
			
			
			
		</author>
	

	<link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />

	<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator>

	
		<entry>
			<id>http://localhost:4000/finance/banking/</id>
			<title>Moving to the United States guide series</title>
			<link href="http://localhost:4000/finance/banking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moving to the United States guide series" />
			<updated>2019-01-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>

			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Mihai Nicolae</name>
					
					
					
						<uri>http://mnicolae.github.io/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>This article in the guide series of moving to the United States covers banking, credit cards &amp; investments.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/finance/banking/">&lt;h1&gt;Before moving&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you move to California, you’re going to have no credit history. To address this short-coming and to have disposable funds immediately, you should set up cross-border banking with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rbcbank.com/index.html&quot;&gt;RBC&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.td.com/ca/en/personal-banking/solutions/cross-border-banking/&quot;&gt;TD Bank&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows you to get a U.S. checking account, a U.S. credit card, order cheques, and transfer money from your Canadian account quickly and without fees. Make sure to set up cross-border banking 1-2 months before moving, in order for the debit card, credit card and ordered cheques to be mailed to your Canadian address in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also apply for a Canadian American Express. The reason to do so is because American Express takes your Canadian credit history &amp;amp; account history into account to make a decision on your U.S. credit application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;After moving&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Banking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you receive your Social Security Number (SSN) contact your bank in order to link your SSN to your checking account and your credit card with the U.S. credit bureau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For setting up banking with a U.S. bank take your time as there are many options to elect from. &lt;a href=&quot;3&quot;&gt;NerdWallet&lt;/a&gt; is a great resource to help you compare. Check if your employer partners with any credit unions for employee discounts or rebates. Lastly, keep an eye out for banking coupons in your mail, as they will be better than any coupons you can find online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The variables I took into consideration when making my decision, in order of importance, were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;welcome bonus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;monthly maintenance fee and how to waive it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;interest APY&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ATM coverage &amp;amp; out-of-network ATM fee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Credit Cards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Investments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robinhood is available in the U.S. and you can use it to trade stocks for free. Use my &lt;a href=&quot;4&quot;&gt;referral link&lt;/a&gt; and we both get a free share!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>

			
				<category term="finance" />
			
			

			<published>2019-01-05T00:00:00-08:00</published>
		</entry>
	
</feed>